Joseph Maguire Correspondence
University of Notre Dame Archives
Joseph Maguire Correspondence
1933-1949.
MCR
Maguire, Joseph, 1871-1964.
2 linear inches.
University of Notre Dame Archives Notre Dame, Indiana 46556
Legal Status
Private
Scope and Content
Four files of correspondence generated during his tenure as President of St. Edward's University, Austin, Texas, 1934-1937, and as Superior to the Holy Cross Community House at Notre Dame.
St. Edward's was operated by the Indiana Province of the Congregation of Holy Cross, and correspondence reflects this relationship. Includes letters from Fathers Thomas A. Steiner (Assistant Provincial), James A. Burns (Provincial), James W. Donahue (Superior General), and others.
Background
Maguire earned bachelor's and master's degrees from the University of Notre Dame (1886-1893); he joined the Congregation of Holy Cross in 1891.
Steiner, Thomas A.; Burns, James A. (James Aloysius), 1867-1940.; Donahue, James W., 1885-1914.; St. Edward's University, (Austin, Texas) -- Presidents.; Congregation of Holy Cross. Indiana Province.; Maguire, Joseph, 1871-1964.; Universities and colleges -- Administration; College presidents -- Texas.; Letters.
Related Material
Information Services
John W. Cavanaugh Papers
President 1928-1934: Rev. Charles O'Donnell CSC
Notre Dame Presidents' Letters, 1856-1906
Portraits Collection
Congregation of Holy Cross. Indiana Province Records
Richard Sullivan Papers
- Joseph Maguire: Manuscripts, CMCR
  - Thomas A. Steiner to Maguire, 1936/0928; CMCR 1.01
  - Thomas A. Steiner to Maguire, 1936/0723; CMCR 1.02
  - J.A. Burns CSC to Maguire, 1936/0906; CMCR 1.03
  - James W. Donahue CSC to Maguire, 1936/0103; CMCR 1.04
  - Maguire to James Donahue, 1936/0126; CMCR 1.05
  - J.A. Burns to Maguire, 1936/0518; CMCR 1.06
  - John F. O'Hara CSC to Maguire, 1936/0331; CMCR 1.07
  - Thomas A. Steiner to Maguire, 1936/0401; CMCR 1.08
  - J.A. Burns to Maguire, 1936/0624; CMCR 1.09
  - Maguire to J.A. Burns, 1937/0511; CMCR 1.10
  - Maguire to J.A. Burns, 1937/0525; CMCR 1.11
  - J.A. Burns to Maguire, 1937/0615; CMCR 1.12
  - J.A. Burns to Maguire, 1937/0522; CMCR 1.13
  - Maguire to J.A. Burns, 1933/1107; CMCR 1.14
  - James W. Donahue to Maguire, 1934/1103; CMCR 1.15
  - J.A. Burns to Maguire, 1934/0929; CMCR 1.16
  - James W. Donahue to Maguire, 1934/1108; CMCR 1.17
  - J.A. Burns to Maguire, 1936/0628; CMCR 1.18
  - J.A. Burns to Maguire, 1936/0708; CMCR 1.19
  - Maguire to J.W. Donahue, 1935/1001; CMCR 1.20
  - Maguire to J.A. Burns, 1935/0902; CMCR 1.21
  - Maguire to J.A. Burns, 1937/0619; CMCR 1.22
  - Maguire to J.W. Donahue, 1937/0525; CMCR 1.23
  - H.H. Homer to Maguire, 1935/0529; CMCR 1.24
  - J.A. Burns to Maguire, 1936/1223; CMCR 1.25
  - Joe L. Stanton to J.A. Burns, 1937/0511; CMCR 1.26
  - Br. Chrysostom to Maguire, 1937/0625; CMCR 1.27
  - J.A. Burns to Maguire, 1936/0811; CMCR 1.28
  - J.A. Burns to Maguire, 1936/0721; CMCR 1.29
  - J.A. Burns to Maguire, 1936/0707; CMCR 1.30
  - J.A. Burns to Maguire, 1936/0624; CMCR 1.31
  - J.A. Burns to Maguire, 1936/0828; CMCR 1.32
  - J.A. Burns to Maguire, 1936/0616; CMCR 1.33
  - Thomas A. Steiner to Maguire, 1936/0715; CMCR 1.34
  - J.A. Burns to Maguire, 1937/0302; CMCR 1.35
  - Maguire to J.A. Burns, 1937/0504; CMCR 1.36
  - Maguire to J.A. Burns, 1937/0223; CMCR 1.37
  - Maguire to J.A. Burns, 1937/0305; CMCR 1.38
  - Maguire to J.A. Burns, 1937/0305; CMCR 1.39
  - Maguire to J.A. Burns, 1937/0407; CMCR 1.40
  - J.A. Burns to Maguire, 1937/0411; CMCR 1.41
  - J.A. Burns to Maguire, 1937/0303; CMCR 1.42
  - J.A. Burns to Maguire, 1935/0916; CMCR 1.43
  - Maguire to J.A. Burns, 1935/0920; CMCR 1.44
  - Maguire to J.A. Burns, 1935/0912; CMCR 1.45
  - Maguire to J.A. Burns, 1935/0911; CMCR 1.46
  - Burns to Maguire, 1935/0904; CMCR 1.47
  - Burns to Maguire, 1935/0831; CMCR 1.48
  - Burns to Maguire, 1935/0830; CMCR 1.49
  - Maguire to Burns, 1935/0821; CMCR 1.50
  - Burns to Maguire, 1935/0814; CMCR 1.51
  - Maguire to Burns, 1935/0723; CMCR 1.52
  - Burns to Maguire, 1935/0720; CMCR 1.53
  - J.J. O'Brien to Burns, 1935/0722; CMCR 1.54
  - Maguire to Burns, 1935/0708; CMCR 1.55
  - Burns to Maguire, 1935/0702; CMCR 1.56
  - Burns to Maguire, 1935/0704; CMCR 1.57
  - Maguire to Burns, 1935/0718; CMCR 1.58
  - Maguire to Burns, 1935/0702; CMCR 1.59
  - J.J. O'Brien to Maguire, 1935/0702; CMCR 1.60
  - Maguire to Burns, 1935/0702; CMCR 1.61
  - Maguire to Burns, 1935/0628; CMCR 1.62
  - Maguire to Burns, 1935/0624; CMCR 1.63
  - Maguire to Burns, 1935/0622; CMCR 1.64
  - Maguire to Burns, 1935/0717; CMCR 1.65
  - J.J. O'Brien to Burns, 1935/0717; CMCR 1.66
  - Maguire to Burns, 1935/0612; CMCR 1.67
  - Maguire to J.W. Donahue, 1935/0610; CMCR 1.68
  - Maguire to J.W. Donahue, 1937/0620; CMCR 1.69
  - Maguire to Faculty Members of St. Edwards University, 1937/0524; CMCR 1.70
  - Maguire to Burns, 1935/0605; CMCR 1.71
  - Maguire to Burns, 1935/0603; CMCR 1.72
  - James V. Allred to Maguire, 1937/0514; CMCR 1.73
  - Burns to Maguire, 1937/0502; CMCR 1.74
  - Hugh O'Donnell to Maguire, 1937/0427; CMCR 1.75
  - Maguire to ?, 1936/0406; CMCR 1.76
  - A. Lester Pierce to Principal, nd; CMCR 1.77
  - Maguire to Norman Johnson, 1937/0224; CMCR 1.78
  - J.W. Donahue to Maguire, 1936/0520; CMCR 1.79
  - James Allred to Maguire, 1937/0520; CMCR 1.80
  - Thomas Steiner to James Allred, 1937/0517; CMCR 1.81
  - P.J. Horkin to James A. Burns, 1937/0528; CMCR 1.82
  - Maguire to Eugene Burke, 1937/0417; CMCR 1.83
  - Maguire to Eugene Burke, 1937/0417; CMCR 1.84
  - Maguire to Jos. Burke, 1937/0417; CMCR 1.85
  - Maguire to Burns, 1937/0417; CMCR 1.86
  - Br. Chrysostom to Maguire, 1936/0723; CMCR 1.87
  - Burns to Maguire, 1937/0426; CMCR 1.88
  - Maguire to John O'Brien, 1937/0223; CMCR 1.89
  - Maguire to Lester Pierce, 1937/0610; CMCR 1.90
  - Maguire to Matt. Schumacher, 1937/0225; CMCR 1.91
  - Maguire to Burns, 1936/0616; CMCR 1.92
  - Maguire to Burns, 1936/0617; CMCR 1.93
  - Burns to Maguire, 1935/0615; CMCR 1.94
  - Letter of Suggestions for Changes in Personel, CMCR 1.95
  - Suggestions for Replacements for St. Edwards for 1936, CMCR 1.96
  - Burns to Maguire, 1935/0824; CMCR 1.97
  - Byrne to Maguire, 1935/0422; CMCR 1.98
  - Committee on Guidance to Mrs. Masterson, 1935/0723; CMCR 1.99
  - Burns to James O'Brien, 1935/0720; CMCR 1.100
  - Maguire to Burns, 1936/0525; CMCR 1.101
  - Newspaper Clipping, "New Teachers' Rules Listed", CMCR 1.102
  - Freshman class listings of St. Edward's University, 1934; CMCR 1.103
  - Freshman class listings of St. Edward's University, 1936; CMCR 1.104
  - Report of the Co-operative lesting bureau, CMCR 1.105
  - Maguire to Burns, 1936/0906; CMCR 1.105
  - 2 statements of Operating Costs for St. Edward's`University 1934/0616 - 1936/0615, CMCR 1.106
  - John Lacey to Maguire, 1936/0401; CMCR 1.107
  - Jos. J. Ryan to Maguire, 1936/0321; CMCR 1.108
  - Question and Answer sheets re St. Edward's University, CMCR 1.109
  - Lester Pierce to Maguire, 1937/0524; CMCR 1.110
  - Maguire to Pat Haggerty, 1937/0721; CMCR 1.111
  - Burns to Maguire, 1934/0714; CMCR 1.112
  - Burns to Maguire, 1935/1021; CMCR 1.113
  - Thomas Steiner to Maguire, 1935/1021; CMCR 1.114
  - Thomas Steiner to Maguire, 1940/0723; CMCR 2.01
  - Maguire to Edward Heston, 1944/0606; CMCR 2.02
  - Maguire to Charles McCarthy, 1944/0330; CMCR 2.03
  - Maguire to Richard Sullivan, 1944/0330; CMCR 2.04
  - Charles McCarthy to Maguire, 1944/0325; CMCR 2.05
  - Maguire to Thomas Steiner, 1944/0610; CMCR 2.06
  - M.M. Walker to Thomas Steiner, 1945/1022; CMCR 2.07
  - Maguire to A.G. Brakore, 1945/1109; CMCR 2.08
  - A.G. Brakore to Thomas Steiner, 1945/1030; CMCR 2.09
  - Thomas Steiner to Maguire, 1945/1108; CMCR 2.10
  - M.M. Walker to Maguire, 1945/1105; CMCR 2.11
  - Felix Duffey to Michael Early, 1944/0515; CMCR 2.12
  - Richard Sullivan to Maguire, 1944/0517; CMCR 2.13
  - Felix Duffey to Maguire, 1944/0515; CMCR 2.14
  - Richard Sullivan to Maguire, 1943/0610; CMCR 2.15
  - Richard Collentine to Thomas Steiner, 1938/0408; CMCR 2.16
  - Richard Collentine to Thomas Steiner (duplicate), 1938/0408; CMCR 2.17
  - Thomas Steiner to Richard Collentine, 1940/0401; CMCR 2.18
  - John Cavanaugh to Richard Collentine, 1938/1029; CMCR 2.19
  - Burns to Richard Collentine, 1938/0721; CMCR 2.20
  - Thomas Steiner to Richard Collentine, 1940/0401; CMCR 2.21
  - Thomas Steiner to Maguire, 1946/0510; CMCR 2.22
  - Subprobation form for proposed New York, 1935/01; CMCR 2.23
  - Estimated cost of Plumbing alterations`(community house), 1935/0105; CMCR 2.24
  - Br. Augustus to Steiner, 1934/0105; CMCR 2.25
  - Br. Augustus to Steiner, 1934/0109; CMCR 2.26
  - Six letters of Admission to Profession- CSC, CMCR 2.27
  - CSC = Congregation of Holy Cross, CMCR 2.27
  - Thomas Steiner to Maguire, 1946/0107; CMCR 2.28
  - Admission to Eugene Gormley, 1945/1204; CMCR 2.29
  - Admission to Vincent Demsko, 1945/1204; CMCR 2.30
  - Admission to Leonard Bombardier, 1945/1204; CMCR 2.31
  - Thomas Steiner to Maguire, 1946/0219; CMCR 2.32
  - Thomas Steiner to Maguire, 1946/0402; CMCR 2.33
  - Thomas Steiner to Maguire, 1946/0410; CMCR 2.34
  - Maguire to Thomas Steiner, 1946/0518; CMCR 2.35
  - Thomas Steiner to Maguire, 1945/1024; CMCR 2.36
  - Cletus Rose to Maguire, 1945/1030; CMCR 2.37
  - G.A. Farabaugh to Maguire, 1945/1006; CMCR 2.38
  - Employer's First Report of Injury (Anton Wasnalski), CMCR 2.39
  - Br. Alcuin to Maguire, 1945/0728; CMCR 2.40
  - J. Brass to Maguire, 1945/0713; CMCR 2.41
  - Br. Alcuin to Jos. Fiedler, 1945/0713; CMCR 2.42
  - Jos. Fiedler to Maguire, 1945/0711; CMCR 2.43
  - Frank Burger to Maguire, 1945/0723; CMCR 2.44
  - Michael Driscoll to Maguire, 1945/0801; CMCR 2.45
  - Maguire to Michael Driscoll, 1945/0803; CMCR 2.46
  - J.J. Sechowski to Superior, 1945/0628; CMCR 2.47
  - C.E. Reilly to Employment Department ND, 1942/1222; CMCR 2.48
  - Christopher O'Toole to Maguire, 1944/0920; CMCR 2.49
  - J.H. Fiedler to Maguire, 1944/0923; CMCR 2.50
  - Richard Grimm to Maguire, 1943/0314; CMCR 2.51
  - Br. Owen to Maguire, 1942/1114; CMCR 2.52
  - Br. Stanislaus to Maguire, 1943/0928; CMCR 2.53
  - Ph. Vanier to Maguire, 1943/0928; CMCR 2.54
  - Maguire to William Robinson, nd; CMCR 2.55
  - William Robinson to Maguire, 1943/0906; CMCR 2.56
  - Maguire to A.J. Huegel, 1943/0808; CMCR 2.57
  - Frank Burger to Maguire, 1945/0319; CMCR 2.58
  - Richard Sullivan to Maguire, 1942/1124; CMCR 2.59
  - Joseph Hart to Maguire, nd; CMCR 2.60
  - Richard Sullivan to Maguire, 1945/0518; CMCR 2.61
  - Felix Duffey to Maguire, 1945/0514; CMCR 2.62
  - Richard Sullivan to Maguire, 1943/0215; CMCR 2.63
  - Excerpts from letter from Msgr. Ready, N.C.W.C. (2), nd; CMCR 2.64
  - Registration under the Selective Training and`Services Act, CMCR 2.65
  - Maguire to Hugh O'Donnell, 1940/1209; CMCR 2.66
  - Maguire to Hugh O'Donnell, 1945/0120; CMCR 2.67
  - Albert Cousineau to Maguire, 1949/0206; CMCR 3.01
  - Father Kenny to Maguire, 1944/1025; CMCR 3.02
  - Jerry Folsonie to ?, nd; CMCR 3.03
  - Annual Banquet Program, 1927/0101; CMCR 3.04
  - ? to Charles O'Donnell, 1924/0908; CMCR 3.05
  - St. Edward's University to Steiner, nd; CMCR 3.06
  - J.H. Fiedler to Maguire, 1946/0513; CMCR 3.07
  - William Robinson to "Dear Father", 1946/0510; CMCR 3.08
  - Hugh O'Donnell to Maguire, 1945/0123; CMCR 3.09
  - Maguire to William Molony, 1945/0329; CMCR 3.10
  - Maguire to William Lallow, 1943/0629; CMCR 3.11
  - Maguire to Francis Remler, 1942/0830; CMCR 3.12
  - Francis Remler to Maguire, 1942/0915; CMCR 3.13
  - C.E. Leutz to Maguire, 1942/1021; CMCR 3.14
  - Maguire to John DeGroote, 1941/0116; CMCR 3.15
  - William Robinson to Maguire, 1945/0316; CMCR 3.16
  - Richard Grimm to Maguire, 1941/0301; CMCR 3.17
  - Maguire to Richard Grimm, 1941/0305; CMCR 3.18
  - Richard Grimm to Maguire, 1941/0310; CMCR 3.19
  - Richard Grunenberg to Maguire, 1941/0423; CMCR 3.20
  - Maguire to Richard Grunenberg, 1941/0425; CMCR 3.21
  - Joseph Pendl to Maguire, 1941/0427; CMCR 3.22
  - Maguire to Joseph Pendl, 1941/0502; CMCR 3.23
  - Dr. Lisewski to Maguire, 1941/0523; CMCR 3.24
  - Maguire to Lisewski, 1941/0528; CMCR 3.25